所以如果你要找候选人这些都是他们要问你的问题
So if you're calling a candidate,
these are questions they're gonna ask you,
或者你应该准备好回答这个问题
or you should be prepared to answer these.
面试过程有几个步骤 ?
How many steps are in
the interview process?
我想知道
I wanna know.
有公司我拒绝接受采访我接到电话
There are companies that I've declined
the interview for, I had a phone call,
我说面试的步骤有多好吗
it was nice and cordial, and
I said how many steps in the interview?
有个电话屏蔽然后还有一个电话屏幕
Well there's a phone screening and
then there's another phone screen and
然后还有七到八回合
then seven to eight rounds alongside.
假设我已经过去了
Let's say I'm pass.
我只是在做这些事就像我不想接受采访一样
I'm just doing this for of course anyways,
like I don't really wanna interview.
但我肯定不想花三四天的时间
But I certainly don't wanna take three,
four days of my time.
但他们应该知道如果他们不认识
But they should know that after that,
if they don't know them,
他们没有一个好的过程
they don't have a good process and
这可能不是最好的面试经验
that may not be the best
interviewing experience.
这很有趣
And this is funny.
事实上这对我来说很有趣对你来说这很有趣
Actually, it's funny to me,
it'll be funny to you in a second.
你会觉得很难采访到大的公司，所以谷歌，
Would you think it's hard to interview
at the big FAANG companies, so Google,
苹果，微软，还是创业公司 ?
Apple, Microsoft, or a startup?
我觉得在大公司面试有点容易
I think interviewing at the big
companies is a little easier.
挑战是否更艰巨 ?
Are the challenges harder?
也许你知道你要在公司做些什么因为他们已经做了
Maybe but you know what you're going to
get at the companies because they've done
数十年甚至几十年
this for years, decades even.
他们有一个招聘经理的过程。
They have a process for
the hiring manager talks to you.
然后这个人来了
And then this person comes on,
他们有一个整体的人，他们有一个科学的。
they have a whole panel of people,
they have it down to a science.
Startups 很容易，可能很难。
Startups could be easy, could be hard.
你不知道你要得到什么
You don't know what you're going to get.
因为通常是像我这样的人
Because it's usually some guy like me.
就像垃圾一样我今天有个面试
It's like crap, I got an interview today.
让我来为 JavaScript 工程师找个问题
Let me Google interview questions for
JavaScript engineers like, yeah,
这个看起来很酷
this one looks hard, cool.
这就是你经常得到的东西
That's what you get a lot of time.
所以了解过程和
So understand the process and
如果你接受采访请你有个过程
if you're giving the interview,
please have a process.
就像我反复说的那样因为这很重要
Like I will say this repeatedly
because it's important.
你在给别人做工作时改变了别人的生活
You are changing someone's life
when you make them a job offer,
当你采访他们的时候
when you interview them.
你改变了他们的生活
You are changing the course of their life.
你说真的
Like, take it seriously.
别专横问你的问题
Don't be arbitrary with your questions.
如果我要出发的话，我就开始在谷歌或者
If I had to start off, I would start and
try to interview at Google or
就像这样
something like that.
我很可能是第一次失败
I would fail wildly
probably the first time.
但他们有这个过程我知道
But they have this process and
I know that, okay,
这些是他们问的问题，我可以研究。
these are the types of questions that
they ask, I can study for these.
启动，你不知道自己会得到什么。
A startup,
you don't know what you're going to get.
就像你在一家小公司工作一样
So as if you're working
in a small company,
比如有一个过程有你在时间前的这些问题。
like have a process have these
questions you have in front of time.
但最重要的是，至少知道要执行的步骤数
But above all, have know at least
the number of steps you're going
在面试过程中
to be in the interview process.
这不太不合理
That's not too unreasonable.
另一个问题是你的工程队有多大 ?
Another question is how big
is your engineering team?
也许知道这种事
Probably know things like this.
我想知道我和两万多名工程师
I wanna know, am I working
with 20,000 other engineers or
我和五个工程师一起工作吗
am I working with five engineers?
它改变了动态。
It changes the dynamic.
它改变了我对一家公司的影响
It changes the influence I'm
gonna have on a company.
我要采访哪个团队 ?
Which team would I be interviewing for?
我要做什么
What am I gonna be doing?
这个很直接但是
This one's pretty straightforward but
你会对那些无法告诉你的人大吃一惊
you'd be surprised the number of
people that couldn't tell you.
他们会喜欢的我们会知道的
They'll be like, we'll see.
你为什么跟我说话
Why are you talking to me?
你显然有开口
You clearly have openings.
你的开口是什么
What are the openings that you have?
贵公司的文化是什么 ?
What is the culture like at your company?
工作辛苦吗 ?
Is it work hard, play hard?
是很轻松很容易吗
Is it it's very relaxed and easy going?
我们是作为一个团队来庆祝胜利吗
Is it we celebrate wins
together as a team?
我们每晚都出去吃饭
We go out for dinner every night.
有些人也许会和你一起，有些人可能不会。
Some of these may vibe with you,
some of them may not.
你应该准备好让一个候选人来问你这些问题。
You should be prepared for
a candidate to ask you these questions.
我喜欢的是谁是你的竞争对手
What I like is, who are your competitors?
这种情况告诉你它是什么样的公司。
That kind of tells you what
sort of company it is.
我们就像对付工业巨头一样
We're like we're going against
the titans of industry.
你们两个人多大 ?
How big are you two people?
你就像很酷
You're like, cool.
我在等那个挑战者
I'm waiting for that challenger.
不我有个孩子在路上
No, I've got a kid on the way.
我真的不想在小启动时冒这个风险。
I really don't want to take
that risk in a small startup.
这很公平但是他们准备问你这些问题
That's fair, but be prepared that they're
going to ask you these sort of questions
以及我在做什么项目
and what sort of projects what I work on.
作为招聘经理招聘人员，您可能应该了解他们所做的一些事情。
As a hiring manager recruiter, you should
probably know some of the things they're
尤其是雇佣一个高级的人
probably gonna work on,
especially for hiring someone senior.
我要承认，我不需要做，我不想做数据库迁移。
I like admittedly, I don't need to do,
I don't want to do database migrations.
我不想做这些
I don't want to do them.
我不想手动将数据转换为 Excel 电子表格。
And I don't want to do manually converting
data into an Excel spreadsheet.
你也许得这么做
You might have to do that though.
你可能会说，嘿，你知道，我们会做些这些
You might say, hey, you know,
we're going to do some of this and
那我们就去做些凉爽的事
then we'll do the cool stuff.
那就好，但对他们要做的事情有个想法
That's fine, but have an idea about
the sort of thing they're going to be
在未来的工作中
working on in the future.